Guide to the Jonathan Edwards Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings of Jonathan Edwards, c. 1720-84; Series I; 10.3; (21 boxes)
  - SERMONS
    - PS. 45:9: "The church is called the queen because of her relation to this glorious King" (p. 4), 1743 Dec (Box 2, Folder 143)
    - PS. 45:15: "They shall enter into the king's palace [text]... 1. Shew how heaven is the King's palace...3. Describe the character of the people that shall enter there..." (p. 4), 1744 Mar (Box 2, Folder 144)
    - PS. 51:17: "A broken heart is an acceptable sacrifice to God" (p. 4), 1733 Mar (Box 2, Folder 145)
      "For a fast day"
    - PS. 55:12-14: "Men are not sufficient positively to determine the state of the souls of others that are of God's visible people" (p. 1), 1741 Sep (Box 2, Folder 146)
    - PS. 60:9-12: "I. If God be pleased to forsake a people and not to go forth with their armies, defeat and confusion is like to be the consequence...", 1755 Aug 28 (Box 2, Folder 147)
      "Fast after General Braddock's defeat"
    - PS. 61:2: "Christ is as an high rock on which persons may stand above the floods that otherwise would overwhelm them" (p. 2), 1747 Jul (Box 2, Folder 148)
    - PS. 65:2: "Tis the character of the Most High God, that he is a God that answers prayer" (p. 2), 1735/6, 1752 (Box 2, Folder 149)
      "Fast on occasion of the sickness at the East Ward"
    - PS. 65:9: "that God by the exercises of is common bounty towards men shews that he has an all sufficiency for the supply of their wants" (p. 2), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 150)
    - PS. 65:11: "That we ought to praise God for annual blessings" (p. 2), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 151)
      Probably a Thanksgiving sermon
    - PS. 66:3: "All that natural men do in religion is altogether forced" (p. 2), 1735 Aug (Box 2, Folder 152)
    - PS. 66:5: "That tis to the glory of God that he is terrible in his doings towards the children of men" (p. 2), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 153)
    - PS. 66:18: "Tis in vain for any to expect to have their prayers heard as long as they continue in the allowance of sin" (p. 2), 1739 Mar 29 (Box 2, Folder 154)
    - PS. 66:18: "1. Shew when a person may be said in the sense of the text to regard iniquity in his heart..." (p. 2), 1744 Apr 12 (Box 2, Folder 155)
    - PS. 71:5: "It behooves young persons to seek that they may be converted while they are young" (p. 2), [ca. late 1730's] (Box 2, Folder 156)
    - PS. 72:6: "That Christ in communicating himself and dispensing his benefits does as it were come down as the rain on the mown grass" (p. 4), 1740/1 Jan (Box 2, Folder 157)
      "Prepared for a sacrament"
    - PS. 73:18-19: "That those that are in a natural condition have reason to be always in fear of being destroyed" (p. 4) (Box 2, Folder 158)
    - PS. 73:25: "Tis the spirit of a truly godly man to prefer God before all other things either in heaven or earth" (p. 3), 1736 Apr (Box 2, Folder 159)
    - PS. 78:5-7: "The religious education of children is one of the principle means of grace that God has appointed in his church" (p. 3), 1744/5, 1755 (Box 2, Folder 160)
      "Quarterly lecture Feb 1744/5"
    - PS. 78:25: "Those that spiritually partake of Christ, they eat angels' food" (p. 3), 1754, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 161)
    - PS. 78:36-37: "Tis heinous wickedness to make false profession of religion when the heart is not right, and so not to be steadfast in God's covenant" (p. 1), 1751 Dec (Box 2, Folder 162)
    - PS. 78:57: "Subject: The backsliding of such as are the visible people of God" (p. 2), 1743 Jun (Box 2, Folder 163)
    - PS. 82:6-7: "That great men are as liable to death as others" (p. 2), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 164)
    - PS. 84:3: "Christ is the believer's home", 1747 Apr (Box 2, Folder 165)
    - PS. 84:10: "A day spent in the house of God in a right manner is better than a thousand spent in sin and in the enjoyment of the things of this world" (p. 1), 1752 May
      See: Box 13, folder 963
      Preached to Stockbridge Indians before Sacrament
    - PS. 89:6: "God is infinitely exalted in gloriousness and excellency above all created beings" (p. 3)
      See: Box 13, folders 964-965
    - PS. 89:15: Text: "Blessed are the people that know the joyful sound", 1742 Jul (Box 2, Folder 166)
    - PS. 89:15: "The Gospel of Jesus Christ is a joyful sound. It is so both on account as it contains tidings of deliverance from evil and as it exhibits and declares good things to the children of men", 1756 (Box 3, Folder 167)
      "At Hadley"
    - PS. 90:5-6: "Man is fitly compared to grass that so often in the morning is green and flourishing but in the evening cut down and withereth" (p. 4), 1734-57 (Box 3, Folder 168)
      Preached to Stockbridge Indians in June 1753
    - PS. 90:12: "That our time here is so short and uncertain that we had great need wisely to improve it" (p. 5) (Box 3, Folder 169)
    - PS. 94:8-11: "There is an extreme and brutish blindness in things of religion that naturally possesses the hearts of mankind" (p. 3), three sermons, 1739/40 Feb (Box 3, Folder 170)
    - PS. 94:10: "Those that are of God's own people have much more reason to fear God's chastisements for their sins than others" (p. 4), 1739/40 Feb (Box 3, Folder 171)
    - PS. 94:12: "He is a happy man though an afflicted one, whom God chastens and teaches out of his word" (p. 2) (Box 3, Folder 172)
    - PS. 94:12: "Blessed is the man whom thou chastenest [text]. God's dealings with the righteous and wicked are here compared", 1745/6 Feb (Box 3, Folder 173)
      "At Pascommuck"
    - PS. 95:7-8: "That it is our great duty forthwith without any delay to hearken to God's voice" (p. 7), n.d.
      See: Box 13, folder 966
    - PS. 102:25-26: "That this present world shall one day come to an end" (p. 3)
      See: Box 13, folders 967-968
    - PS. 106:5: "They above all others are truly blessed ones that are admitted to see the good of God's chosen, and to rejoice in the gladness of God's nation, and to glory with his inheritance" (p. 5), 1737 Aug (Box 3, Folder 174)
    - PS. 108:4: "God is a Being of transcendent mercy" (p. 2) (Box 3, Folder 175)
    - PS. 110:2: "Christ will rule in the midst of his enemies" (p. 3), 1733 May (Box 3, Folder 176)
    - PS. 110:4: "Subject: Christ's priestly office...It is this office of Christ in the execution of which he makes atonement for the sin of men and procures for them the favor and blessing of God" (p. 3), 1744, 1755 (Box 3, Folder 177)
    - PS. 111:5: "God never fails in any instance of faithfulness to the covenant engagements he has entered into in behalf of any of mankind" (p. 2), 1745 Aug (Box 3, Folder 178)
    - PS. 112:1: "Good men are happy men" (p. 1), 1750/1 Feb
      See: Box 13, folder 969
      Preached to Mohawks
    - PS. 113:6: "The subject I intend to insist on from these words is, God's humbling himself to behold the things that are in heaven" (p. 1), 1742 Nov 11 (Box 3, Folder 179)
    - PS. 115:1: "That it is the temper of the truly godly to delight to exalt God and to lay themselves low" (p. 2)
      See: Box 13, folder 970
    - PS. 115:17-18: "The blessedness of the saints in heaven consists very much in continually praising and glorifying God" (p. 4), 1747 Nov 26 (Box 3, Folder 180)
    - PS. 116:12: "When persons have received signal mercies of God, it becomes 'em to be earnestly inquisitive what they shall render to the Lord for all his benefits towards them" (p. 3), 1735/6 Feb (Box 3, Folder 181)
    - PS. 118:6-9: "I. How men are apt to trust men..." (p. 1), 1756 Jul (Box 3, Folder 182)
      Stockbridge Fast
    - PS. 119:1-3: "As we would approve ourselves true saints we must obey God's commands [or "commandments"] universally, perseveringly, and with our whole hearts" (p. 3), 1744/5 Feb (Box 3, Folder 183)
    - PS. 119:1-6: "I. He that is a good man walks in a holy way..." (p. 1), 1754 Mar
      See: Box 13, folder 971
    - PS. 119:2: "That the way to receive the blessed fruits of religion is to practice it with our whole hearts" (p. 3), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 184)
    - PS. 119:3: "The spirit that godly men are of is a spirit to be perfectly holy" (p. 2), 1737, 1757 (Box 3, Folder 185)
    - PS. 119:18: "Men are naturally blind, so that they don't [see] the main things in the word of God" (p. 1), [1751?] Oct
      See: Box 13, folder 972
      Stockbridge
    - PS. 119:56: "When persons have strictly adhered to their duty under temptation & opposition they commonly afterwards in this world find that benefit & reward of it that makes glad they have done so" (p. 5), 1740 Sep (Box 3, Folder 186)
    - PS. 119:60: "That we ought to make religion our present and immediate business" (p. 2)
      See: Box 13, folder 973
    - PS. 119:60: "Man is made to differ from all the brute creatures in that respect, that he is capable of knowing God and knowing his will" (p. 1), 1751 Sep
      See: Box 13, folder 974
    - PS. 119:60-61: "Men ought to be much in thinking of their own ways" (p. 1), 1754 Mar
      See: Box 13, folder 975
    - PS. 119:108: "In a right thanksgiving to God, heart and mouth and practice all go together" (p. 3), 1744 Nov (Box 3, Folder 187)
    - PS. 119:140: "Holy persons love holy things for their holiness" (p. 2), 1744, 1754 (Box 3, Folder 188)
    - PS. 119:162: "The joy that is experienced by a soul, that spiritual good exhibited in the word of God, is often times like the joy of him that finds great spoils in war" (p. 1), 1749 Nov (Box 3, Folder 189)
      Material from a discussion by Jonathan Edwards of the grounds on which a wife may leave her husband on pp. 2-3
    - PS. 126:5-6: "The great work and business that we have to do in order to our spiritual and eternal happiness is fitly represented by the business of an husband-man" (p. 3), 1742 Sep (Box 3, Folder 190)
    - PS. 127:2: "That those that trust in themselves and seek satisfaction and rest for their souls in their own strength do commonly weary themselves with many vain attempts" (p. 1), 1736 May (Box 3, Folder 191)
    - PS. 136:1: "That all the great works of God from the beginning of the world to the end of it are works of mercy to his people" (p. 11), 1736 Nov (Box 3, Folder 192)
    - PS. 139:7-10: "That God is everywhere present" (p. 2), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 193)
    - PS. 139:23-24: "Persons should be much concerned to know, whether they do not live in some way of sin" (p. 3), 1733 Sep (Box 3, Folder 194)
    - PS. 144:12: "Tis a peculiarly lovely and pleasant sight to behold young people walking in the ways of virtue and piety" (p. 3), 1744 Nov (Box 3, Folder 195)
    - PS. 144:15: "The interest of a people mainly consists in the interest of religion among them" (p. 4), 1740 Nov (Box 3, Folder 196)
    - PS 145:15-21: "All creatures in heaven and earth have all their good things from God" (p. 1), 1753 Nov 1
      See: Box 13, folder 976
      Thanksgiving, to Stockbridge Indians
    - PS. 147:1: "Its a very decent and comely thing that praise should be given to God" (p. 3)
      See: Box 13, folder 977
    - PROV. 1:24-31: "Christ calls a great deal to wicked men to forsake their sins and come to him and walk in his ways" (p. 1), 1755 Jun
      See: Box 13, folder 978
    - PROV. 1:26-27: "Those that sin away the day of grace shall be wholly cast away by God as to any regard to their welfare" (p. 1), 1744 Mar (Box 3, Folder 197)
    - PROV. 2:1-6: "1. Receive the words of God" "2. Hide God's commandments or lay 'em up carefully" "3. Incline the ear..." (p. 1), 1753 Oct
      See: Box 13, folder 979
    - PROV. 3:15: "To become truly gracious is the highest privilege that ever any of the children of men attain to, or that tis possible that they should wish for" (p. 1), 1749 Aug (Box 3, Folder 198)
    - PROV. 3:16-18: "True religion is no other than the true method of becoming really and durably rich and honorable and joyful" (p. 1), 1750, 1751 (Box 3, Folder 199)
      Preached "at Middletown/ Windsor/ Salem-Village/at Stockbridge"
    - PROV. 4:7: "An interest in Christ should be sought above all things in the world", 1739 Jun (Box 3, Folder 200)
    - PROV. 4:23: "If we have any regard to our salvation it concerns us with all diligence to keep our hearts" (p. 3), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 201)
    - PROV. 5:11-13: "That vicious persons when once they come to taste the bitter fruits of their evil courses, will greatly lament their folly in not hearkening to the counsels and warnings that were given them" (p. 2) (Box 3, Folder 202)
    - PROV. 5:11-13: "Convictions are terrible when they come too late for repentance" (p. 2), 1741 Oct (Box 3, Folder 203)
    - PROV. 6:22: "Grace maintained in lively exercise is of excellent benefit to men as a guide to direct and conduct them in their way" (p. 2), 1749/50, 1752 (Box 3, Folder 204)
    - PROV. 6:22: "Grace maintained in lively exercise is a continual safeguard to a person" (p. 1), 1749/50, 1752 (Box 3, Folder 205)
    - PROV. 6:22: "A person that maintains grace in lively exercise is as it were never alone, but is entertained from within himself with the conversation of a most excellent companion when retired from other company" (p. 2), 1749/50, 1752 (Box 3, Folder 206)
    - PROV. 7:7: "Those young people that spend their youth in sin and vanity act as those that are void of understanding" (p. 4), 1738, 1756 (Box 3, Folder 207)
    - PROV. 8:10: "The grace of God in the heart is better than silver and gold" (p. 1), 1756 May
      See: Box 13, folder 980
    - PROV. 8:17: "Doc. I. They are happy that love Jesus Christ inasmuch as all such are those that he loves..." (p. 1), 1756 Aug (Box 3, Folder 208)
      "English children at a catechizing"
    - PROV. 8:31: "Christ delighted in the thoughts of saving poor sinners before ever the world was made" (p. 1), 1752 Mar
      See: Box 13, folder 981
    - PROV. 8:34: "That the way to obtain grace is daily to wait upon God for it in the use [of] the means of his appointment" (p. 2), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 209)
    - PROV. 8:34-36: "1. What it is to hear Christ" (p. 1), 1752 Apr
      See: Box 13, folder 982
    - PROV. 9:12: "In all that God requires of us and counsels us to in religion, he does but direct us to be friendly to ourselves" (p. 3), 1738, 1751 (Box 3, Folder 210)
    - PROV. 10:24: Text: "The fear of the wicked shall come upon him" (p. 3), 1737 May (Box 3, Folder 211)
    - PROV. 10:24: "The fear of the wicked; it shall come upon him" (p. 1), [text], 1747, 1751 (Box 3, Folder 212)
      "Preached the other sermon on this text at Stockbridge"
    - PROV. 10:24: Text: "The desire of the righteous shall be granted" (p. 1), 1747 Aug (Box 3, Folder 213)
    - PROV. 11:7: "When a wicked man dies all his hope and expectation perishes" (p. 2), 1739 Nov (Box 3, Folder 214)
    - PROV. 11:7: "The vanity of the hopes of wicked men on account of the sad end they come to when they come to die" (p. 2), 1747-55 (Box 3, Folder 215)
      Preached to Stockbridge Indians, "English & Mohawks/Windsor/Pautoosuck /Northampton"
    - PROV. 11:8: "There is an approaching great change in the state of things, wherein things will be turned upside down with regard to the state of the righteous and the wicked" (p. 5), 1750, 1756 (Box 3, Folder 216)
    - PROV. 13:20: "If men will keep company with them that walk in wicked ways, nothing else is to be expected than that they will come to eternal destruction" (p. 1), 1755 Jun
      See: Box 13, folder 983
    - PROV. 14:14: "They that set out in religion and go back again shall have enough of the fruits of it to make them bitterly repent it" (p. 2), 1753, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 217)
      March 1753 sermon preached to Stockbridge Indians
    - PROV. 14:32: "There is a vast difference between the death of a sinner and a saint" (p. 1), 1745 Aug (Box 3, Folder 218)
    - PROV. 14:34: "That the prevailing of sin and wickedness does exceedingly tend to bring calamity and misery upon any people" (p. 2), 1753, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 219)
    - PROV. 15:16: "A man can't enjoy his worldly good things with any true peace and quietness without Godliness" (p. 2), 1748 Dec (Box 3, Folder 220)
    - PROV. 15:24: "There is but one way to heaven and all the rest are ways to hell", 1744 Aug (Box 3, Folder 221)
    - PROV. 16:4: "That wicked men answer the end of their being no other way but in their suffering" (p. 3) (Box 3, Folder 222)
    - PROV. 17:16: "Tis wholly of no benefit to many persons that they have great advantages put into their hands to obtain the grace [of God], because they have no heart to it" (p. 2), 1743 Jun (Box 3, Folder 223)
    - PROV. 17:27: "That the spirit of true godliness is an excellent spirit" (p. 2), 1755, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 224)
    - PROV. 18:10: "How Christ is a strong tower" (p. 1), 1754 Sep
      See: Box 13, folder 984
    - PROV. 19:8: "Self love duly regulated is a thing of great use in religion" (p. 1), 1749, 1752 (Box 3, Folder 225)
    - PROV. 19:8: "God in directing of us to seek after holiness only advises us to be friends to our own souls" (p. 1), 1756 Jun
      See: Box 13, folder 985
    - PROV. 23:5: "That earthly riches are of a very fleeting nature" (p. 2), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 226)
    - PROV. 23:23: "Buy the truth and sell it not", 1742/3 Feb (Box 3, Folder 227)
    - PROV. 24:13-14: "That it would be worth the while to be religious if it were only for the pleasantness of it" (p. 3), n.d.
      See: Box 13, folder 986
    - PROV. 24:13-14: "The directest way that young people can take to spend their youth pleasantly, is to make it the way of virtue and piety", 1734 May (Box 3, Folder 228)
    - (p. 3)
      "Preached at Scantick, Canaan, Hadley, Stockbridge, York, Westfield, East Ward"
    - PROV. 24:20: "There is nothing got by ways of sin" (p. 5), 1736/7 Feb (Box 3, Folder 229)
      "Preached at Springfield"
    - PROV. 24:20: "I shall not raise a doctrine in any other words but shall insist on the words of the text and shall shew...wherein the candle of the wicked is put out" (pp. 3-4), 1737 Oct (Box 3, Folder 230)
    - PROV. 26:11: "That wicked men, tho for a while they may seem to forsake their sins, yet if their natures are not changed they will be very liable to return to them again" (p. 4), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 231)
    - PROV. 27:1: "We ought to behave ourselves every day as though we had not dependence on any other day" (p. 3) (Box 3, Folder 232)
    - PROV. 27:22: "Folly is naturally so rooted and confirmed in men that if God leaves them to themselves, let what will be done with them, they will not learn wisdom" (p. 2), 1733 Nov (Box 3, Folder 233)
    - PROV. 28:1: "Righteousness tends to make a man's heart bold and courageous" (p. 1), 1754 Sep
      See: Box 13, folder 987
    - PROV. 28:2: "Doc. 1. An unsettled state of people's pubic affairs is a token of God's anger against them for their sins" "Doc. 2. The privileges of a community are prolonged and established by the wisdom and righteousness of its members" (p. 4) (Box 3, Folder 234)
    - PROV. 28:13: "God stands ready to forgive every sinner upon his heartily confessing and forsaking his sin" (p. 1), 1752, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 235)
    - PROV. 29:25: "They are safe that trust in God" (p. 2), n.d.
      See: Box 13, folder 988
    - PROV. 30:24-27[28]: "Tis a great point of wisdom in those that have no sufficiency in themselves, to improve the opportunity God gives them to get supplies elsewhere against a time of need" (p. 4), [focus of sermon is v. 25] (Box 3, Folder 236)
    - PROV. 30:24-27[28]: "Tis a great point of wisdom for them that are feeble and defenceless in themselves to see to it that their refuge and dwelling place is strong" (p. 3) [focus of sermon is v.26], 1745 Dec (Box 3, Folder 237)
    - PROV. 30:[24-]27[28]: "Wisdom disposes to peace and union...those that are wise are inclined to union with their fellow creatures" (p. 2) [focus of sermon. is v.27], 1745 Dec (Box 3, Folder 238)
    - PROV 30:24-28: "Wisdom and industry is the way for those that are mean and contemptible to come to riches and heaven" (p. 6), [focus of sermon is v.25], 1745 Dec (Box 3, Folder 239)
    - ECCL. 2:17: "The world may make men miserable, but it never yet made any man happy" (p. 1), 1743 May (Box 3, Folder 240)
    - ECCL. 5:1: "It greatly concerns persons to take heed to themselves how they behave when they go to the house of God and attend the solemn duties of God's publick worship there" (p. 4), 1746 Oct (Box 3, Folder 241)
    - ECCL. 5:4-6: "A being negligent of the fulfillment of solemn vows to God is a thing that eminently exposes 'em to the blast of heaven in everything that concerns them" (p. 4), 1743 Oct (Box 3, Folder 242)
    - ECCL. 6:4: "There are some persons that are born miserable and live in darkness and die in darkness and when they are dead go into eternal darkness" (p. 2), 1742, 1755 (Box 3, Folder 243)
    - ECCL. 7:1: "The day of a Godly man's death is better than the day of his birth" (p. 3), 1734 Jun (Box 3, Folder 244)
    - ECCL. 7:6: "The pleasure of sinful mirth is a worthless vanishing and ruinous pleasure" (p. 3), 1734 Nov (Box 4, Folder 245)
      "Lecture-day night meeting"
    - ECCL. 7:8: "Tis what is more to be regarded how things will be in their end and issue than how they begin" (p. 3) (Box 4, Folder 246)
    - ECCL. 8:8: "When the appointed time of death comes nothing can put it off" (p. 3), 1747, 1756 (Box 4, Folder 247)
    - ECCL. 8:8: "I. Most men are very much afraid of death II. When death appears near, then especially are most men unwilling to die..." (p. 1), 1755 Mar
      See: Box 13, folder 989
    - ECCL. 8:11: "Prop. I. Sentence is pronounced against [every evil work. It is] pronounced by God...", 1748 Jun (Box 4, Folder 248)
    - ECCL. 8:11: "I. That God will punish wicked men", 1753 May
      See: Box 13, folder 990
    - ECCL. 9:10: "That persons had need to make all possible haste to get that work done that must be done and that can't be done after death" (Box 4, Folder 249)
    - ECCL. 9:10: "Persons ought to do what they can for their salvation" (p. 3), 1733 Dec (Box 4, Folder 250)
      Originally stitched together with sermon ECCL. 9:10: "Whatever persons look upon..."
    - ECCL. 9:10: "Whatever persons look upon needful to be done for their own salvation and intend to do at all they should do now" (p. 1), 1733/4 Jan (Box 4, Folder 251)
      Originally stitched together with sermon ECCL. 9:10: "Persons ought to do..." as a continuation of it
    - ECCL. 9:10: "I. What [men] must do. Whatsoever thy hand finds to do. Everything that needs to be done in order to their salvation and in order to their being prepared for death" (p. 1), 1751 Dec
      See: Box 13, folder 991
    - ECCL. 9:12: "Death commonly comes upon ungodly men at an evil time or at a time that is peculiarly inconvenient for them" (p. 3), 1744/5, 1752 (Box 4, Folder 252)
    - ECCL. 11:2: "We ought to prepare for whatever changes may come to pass in the world" (p. 3), 1737 Dec 11 (Box 4, Folder 253)
      "After an earthquake that was Dec 7 at about 11 of clock at night"
    - ECCL. 11:9-10: "When young people will follow their own youthful disposition and indulge themselves in vain mirth or pleasure, God will surely bring 'em into judgment for those things and they will surely end in sorrow" (p. 2), 1746/7, 1755 (Box 4, Folder 254)
    - ECCL. 12:1: "The time of youth is the best time to be improved to religious purposes" (p. 4), n.d. (Box 4, Folder 255)
    - ECCL. 12:1: "By remembering [our Creator] is meant that they should think much of him and that they should seek him and should give him that respect which is proper to give to him that made them" (p. 1), 1750/1 Feb
      See: Box 13, folder 992
      Preached at Stockbridge
    - ECCL. 12:7: "That when a man dies his soul goes to God who gave it" (p. 2) (Box 4, Folder 256)
    - CANT. 1:3: "That Christ Jesus is a person transcendently excellent and desirable" (p. 3) (Box 4, Folder 257)